Eder Ruiz Maria

Manaus, BR

eder.rm82@gmail.com Phone: 069 242424

Summary

I'm passionate about understanding how things work and what fascinates me most is the world of computing. This fascination quickly led me to the world of Linux and Open Source which in those days meant knowing how to use the command line to operate the system.

At university Pascal was the first language I learnt, but C quickly became my favourite programming language. Since then I have had experience with several other languages and paradigms, including Delphi, Pascal, C, Assembly x86, C++, Java, Shell Script, Python, PHP, JavaScript, Prolog, Awk, Lua, Wiring, Matlab, Verilog and HDL. I know some of them deeply, others just superficially. Among the languages that I don't know, some I hope not to need, others I can't wait for the contact, such as R and Go.

My professional experience is very strong in Linux, Embedded Linux, C and microcontrollers. Also I've worked with web applications and mobile (Android). I recently had contact with FPGA, GPU, image processing and computer vision. Topics that also interest me are Operating Systems, Real Time Systems, Distributed Systems, High Availability, Fault Tolerance, Data Science and Cloud Computing.

Feel free to get in touch and to look my detailed professional experiences below. You can find my open source projects at my github account in https://github.com/ederrm.

Education

State University of West Paraná, BSc in Computer Science, December 2009.

Federal University of Santa Catarina, MSc in Automation Engineering, Discipline Distributed System, April 2010.

Experience

Nokia Institute of Technology

Jun 2012 - Jun 2015

Software Engineer

Main Technologies: Linux, C/C++, Raspberry PI, Arduino, Java, JavaScript, BlueZ;

- Contributor in the Official Linux Bluetooth protocol stack;
- Android development (internal e apps);
- Embedded development (Arduino and Respberry PI);
- Web development (webpy, AngularJS, SQLite, RESTFul API)
- C++ Development using QT Library (Desktop and Meego);
- Distributed version control system (git);
- Code review tools (phabricator, gerrit);
- Iterative and incremental agile software development methodology (Scrum);
- CUDA, Matlab, Image Processing, Computer Vision;

Ahgora Systems

Jan 2012 - Jun 2012

Software Engineer

Main Technologies: Linux, C, Lua, git, Device Driver, Kernel, Embedded Softwares;

- Device drivers development to Linux Kernel ARM (atmel at91sam9g20);
- Development of bate-metal firmware to 8051 using ultra low-power (nordic nrf24le1)
- Development of applications to Embedded Linux (C, lua bind)
- Linux development in general using C, shell script;
- Android development (using adb and IOIO);
- Firmware development to keyboard control (quantum qt60248)

• Firmware development to ARM Cortex-M3 (nxp lpc1768)

Digitro Technology

Nov 2009 - Dec 2011

Software Engineer

Main Technologies: Linux, C/C++, Kernel, Devices Driver, Embedded Software;

- Device driver development to Linux Kernel (vortex86mx southbridge gpio, omap5912);
- Device driver development to uClinux (blackfin 536/537);
- Development and customize Bootloader (U-Boot);
- Bare-metal firmware development (HCS08)
- Development of applications to Embedded Linux (C, Socket and GLib);
- Development different kind of application in Linux environment (C, Python, shell);
- Subversion Version Control;

Institute of Applied Technology and Innovation

Feb 2009 - Oct 2009

 $Software\ Engineer$

Main Technologies: Linux, C/C++, PIC, Modbus/RTU, RTAI, Java/JNI, beagleboard;

- Data acquisition using drivers Comedi to national board PCI6143;
- Tasks hard real time using RTAI;
- Development of a serial communication protocol between PC and Microcontroller PIC;
- Application development Modbus/RTU Master;
- Development of an application to comunicate to GPS Garmin 18x USB;
- Integration of native code with Java, using JNI;
- Embedded Linux using beagleboard (OMAP);

Skills Base

Operating System: Linux, Windows NT/XP/Vista/7 and OSX;

Networking: TCP/IP protocol suite;

 $\label{eq:community} \textit{Progamming Languages} : \text{C/C++}, \text{Lua}, \text{PHP}, \text{Python}, \text{JavaScript}, \text{plus some experience with Java};$

Virtualization: VirtualBox, VMWare, plus some experience with Xen;

Languages: Fluent in Portuguese, Intermediate in English and Spanish;

Open Source Projects

• BlueZ: BlueZ is the Bluetooth stack for Linux kernel-based family of operating systems. Its goal is to program an implementation of the Bluetooth wireless standards specifications for Linux.

More Info

• Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ederrm

• Github: https://github.com/ederrm